>> Brian Holt: 让我们继续使用 Memo。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Let's go on to useMemo.
接下来的两个是性能优化，好的。
So the next two are performance
optimizations, okay.
>> Brian Holt: 因此，让我们先看看这首先是如何工作的。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: So let's take a look
at how this works first of all.
请注意，我有一个时钟。
Notice here I have a clock.
而这个时钟又像其他的一样
And this clock again works exactly
like the other one up here,
每秒钟都有进步
that it advances every second.
此组件必须每秒重新呈现。
This component has to
re-render every single second.
React 工作的方式，如果我重新呈示父组件，
The way that React works,
that if I re-render a parent component,
在缺省情况下我也会把所有孩子都重新呈现
just by default, I'm gonna
re-render all the children as well.
是一种性能优化，不用去检查
It's kind of a performance optimization
that they don't have to go check
一切都说如果这改变了
everything, they just say,
well if this changed,
可能在它下面的一切都变了
probably everything underneath it changed.
他们不做额外的检查，对，因为它可能都改变了。
And they don't do all the extra checking,
right, because it probably did all change.
而这些渲染方法一般都非常快，对吧 ?
And these render methods,
in general, are very fast, right?
所以，总的来说，这是一件好事。
So in general,
that's a good thing for it to do.
Cuz React 真的很擅长重新渲染。
Cuz React is really good
at re-rendering things.
只要你写 performant 渲染方法，真的很快，好吗 ?
As long as you write performant render
methods, it's really fast, okay?
问题在于我写了一个有意慢的函数。
The problem comes into is that I
wrote an intentionally slow function.
你不必在意斐波纳契做什么但计算斐波纳契
You don't really have to care about what
Fibonacci does, but computing Fibonacci
数字递归的非常重，对吧 ?
numbers recursively is very heavy, right?
所以我想说的是这个计算
So what I want to say
here is this computation
就在这里 fib，所以这个数字的无花果是一个非常大的操作。
right here fib, so fibonacci of
number is a very heavy operation.
为了证明我的意思
So just to prove my point to you,
如果我开始点击这个，第一个就不坏了。
if I start clicking this,
the first ones are not too bad.
但一到三十左右，它就会变得非常缓慢。
But as soon as this gets to about 30,
it's going to start being really slow.
>> Brian Holt: 对，非常慢。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Right, really slow.
>> Brian Holt: 好，这里有什么问题 ?
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Okay, so
what's the problem here?
如果我有这个而且每次都是重新呈现
Well if I have this, and
this is re-rendering every single time,
这意味着它会每一次都在计算，对吗 ?
that would mean that it would be
computing this every single time, right?
我可能要毁了我的浏览器但会很有趣的
I'm probably gonna crash my browser,
but it'll be fun.
我们来吧
Let's do this.
所以如果我说 const fib = fibonacci(num)，
So if I say, const fib = fibonacci(num),
这就意味着
that means this is going to get
每一次计算一次，对。
computed every single time, right.
现在，一个人的 fibonacci 非常快。
Now right now, fibonacci of one,
it's pretty fast.
等等我已经给你展示了 " 回调"
Wait, I've shown you, useCallback.
问题仍然相同，因为它仍使用斐波纳契数。
The point is still the same because
it still uses Fibonacci numbers.
>> Brian Holt: 所以现在， >> Brian Holt: 因此忽略此。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: So right now,
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: So ignore this.
我们很快就会回来的
We'll come back to
useCallback in just a second.
>> Brian Holt: 但他们都使用了斐波纳契数，所以是同一点。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: But they both use Fibonacci
numbers, so it's the same point.
所以注意，这真的很缓慢。
So notice, this is really slow right now.
>> Brian Holt: 对，现在不是重新呈现，所以一切都很好，对吧 ?
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Right, right now it's not
re-rendering, so everything's okay, right?
所以它计算了它一切都很好
So it computed it and everything was fine.
但如果我点击这个 useMemo 将其从绿色改为红色，
But if I click on this useMemo to
change this from green to red,
它会重新计算这个
it's going to recalculate this.
所以如果我点击这个
So if I click on this,
我点击它，看它变红花了多久，对吧 ?
I click on it, look how long it
took that to change to red, right?
因为它在这里重新计算斐波纳契序列对吧
Because it's recalculating
the Fibonacci sequence here, right?
如果我们不需要每次都重新计算，岂不是很棒吗 ?
Wouldn't it be great if we didn't have
to recalculate that every single time?
所以如果我把这个改为使用
So if I change this to be useMemo
这里， >> Brian Holt: 我给它的功能
here,
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Where I give it a function
如何重新计算此属性，然后再重新计算其依赖关系，就像使用效果一样。
of how to recalculate this and then its
dependency, just like you use effect.
让我们把这个恢复到另一个大号
Let's get this up back to
another big number here.
>> Brian Holt: 可能应该刚刚开始 40 或
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Probably should
have just started with 40 or
那样的东西对吧
something like that, right?
好吧这现在又大了对吧
Okay, so
this is now really big again, right?
但是注意，我现在可以来回改变这个，没问题，
But notice, I can now change this back and
forth, no problem,
因为它不是每次都重新计算
because it's not recalculating
every single time.
你多久能用这个 ?
How often will you use this?.
说实话也许永远不会吧
Honestly, maybe never, right?
这不是一个很典型的问题，但是有钩子可以产生，对，
This is not a very typical problem,
however, with hooks it can arise, right,
你每次都在计算东西
where you're computing
things every single time.
这就是 useMemo 所做的事情。
So that's what useMemo does.
你给它一个计算什么东西的功能然后给它
You give it a function of how to compute
something and then you give it its
仅当其依赖关系已更改时，才会对其进行重新计算。
dependencies and it will only re-compute
it when its dependencies have changed.